It seems today that all you see
Is violence in movies and sex on TV
But where are those
good old-fashioned values
On which we used to rely?
Lucky there's a family guy
Lucky there's a man who
positively can do
All the things that make us
Laugh and cry
He's a family guy
Hi, it's me, Peter, your TV cartoon pal.
You know, Lois has been bitching lately
that I watch too much TV
and don't read enough books,
so I went to the library
and picked up three books
by the greatest author
of the last thousand years, Stephen King.
And tonight I'd like
to share them with you.
We begin with a little tale
called Stand by Me,
about four young boys
who went looking for a dead body
and instead found themselves
and also a dead body.
The year was 1955,
and the voice in my head was
that of Richard Dreyfuss.
I never had friends
like the ones I had when I was 12.
There was me, Petey Lachance.
Anyone else fed up
with this over-saturation of media?
Three channels and still nothing on.
Then there was Joey Duchamp.
The voice in his head was Roy Scheider.
How are you, Richard?
Fine, Roy.
- How are you?
Good, good.
We should grab a drink
sometime and catch up.
- Maybe reminisce about Jaws.
Great.
You should give me a call sometime.
My number is 555...
Wait, wait. What? 555?
- Yeah.
You know what, Richard?
If you don't want to have drinks,
just say so.
You don't have to be a dick about it.
Oh, please! Make the voices stop!
And then there was Quag
Chambers. He was the leader of our gang.
He had sex when he was five
and committed his first rape
when he was 10,
rape, of course, being legal in the '50s.
Beat those cards, fellas.
Giggity Giggity '50s Giggity.
Hey, you guys.
Finally, there was Cleve Brown,
my pudgy black friend.
I can still see him now,
all pudgy and black.
Cleve, please.
We're busy looking at Playboy.
Look at the way
these women starve themselves.
This one can't be more than 180 pounds.
This is way better than Playboy.
Do you guys want to see a dead body?
Cleve, it's 1955.
Please re-enter the clubhouse in
a more stereotypically animated fashion.
Lord almighty! I done seen me
a dead body down by the lake.
Sho' 'nough, I thought I'd go deef
and dumb when I saw me that dead body.
Cleve, calm down.
You're not making any sense.
Every day it's a-getting closer...
Anything was possible
as we set out that day,
except contracting AIDS
because AIDS had not yet
been invented by the government
in an effort to eradicate
the homosexual community.
Have gun, will travel
reads the card of a man
A knight without armor in a savage land
Okay, I got another one.
Show me that smile again
Show me that smile
Don't waste another minute on your crying
We decided to cut through
Old Man Pressman's junkyard,
even though legend had it
that any kid caught scaling the fence
ran the risk of being attacked
by the old man's dog,
who would charge to the cry of
'"Chopper, sic balls. '"
I got a bad feeling about this.
Hey! What are you kids doing?
Oh, no! It's him!
That's right. I'm Old Man Pressman.
I own the junkyard.
I'm cranky 'cause all my stuff is junk.
Why can't I have nice things?
Chopper, sic them. Sic them, boy!
Now, he said, '"Sic them, boy. '"
But what I heard was,
'"Chopper, talk to disfigured
World War II veterans
'"who aren't as bitter as they should be. '"
Glad I could do my part.
I think you may have done too much.
Hey, how about this
brand new thing called rock and roll?
Even though it was just invented,
we already remember it fondly.
Here's Little Richard with Piano Riff Woo.
Woo!
Fuck that.
Man, this trip is dangerous.
Couldn't we have just taken a bus?
No... black guy.
Guys? Anyone know
when the next train is scheduled?
Don't worry. If a train comes,
I'll warn you in slow motion.
Train!
My legs!
Another train!
What an odd, clustered train schedule!
- Hey, sorry you got paralyzed, Joey.
- That's all right.
Thanks for going all the way back
to the junkyard to get me this wheelchair.
Boy, was Old Man Pressman angry.
We talked into the night,
the kind of talk that seemed important
until you discover girls.
This House Un-American
Activities Committee is a travesty.
And if we go into French Indochina,
it'll take us 30 years to get out.
Levittown-type housing communities
will replace individualism
with fear and conformity.
What do you think of that new kid
at school, Marty McFly?
Seems like he just showed up
out of nowhere.
Well, there it is.
None of us could breathe.
The twisted and mangled body
we had come to see
was far more disgusting
than any of us could ever have imagined.
He's nasty.
Out of my way, you little pip-squeaks.
I'm taking credit for finding this body.
It was the meanest guy
in town, Ace, and his whole gang,
Beast Man, Mer-Man and,
for some reason, Norm from Cheers.
Hey, gang.
What, are we beating somebody up?
Now, get lost. We'll take it from here.
Kiss my grits, you cheap dime-store hood.
This ain't over, Lachance.
I mean, you have a gun right now.
But tomorrow I'll get a gun
and come to your house and kill you.
Oh. Yeah, I guess you could do that, huh?
I mean, we live in the same town.
And I can't just be on my guard
for the rest of my life.
Boy, that is a major hole in this story.
Okay, take the body.
We never forgot
that wonderful summer.
And eventually we all went
our separate ways.
Joey learned to live
without the use of his legs
and even went on to create
a wheelchair-type rugby game
called Don't Feel Sorry For Us Ball.
Cleve grew up
and went on to marry Rebecca Romijn.
Actually, I'm not even joking about that.
The fat kid from Stand by Me
is now married to Rebecca Romijn.
Can you believe that?
I swear to God. Look it up on the Internet.
Doesn't that piss you off?
Quag grew up to become
a famous Hollywood actor.
Unfortunately, about a week ago,
he took an overdose of designer drugs
at The Viper Room.
He died on the curb outside,
and now we're left with a harelipped
reminder of what might have been.
Hi. Welcome back from commercials.
Joaquin Phoenix, if you're still watching,
you are a good sport and a trouper,
and you passed our test,
and you can be our friend.
And now for a segment we like
a little less than the first and the last.
Here's Misery.
Marcia, I've done it.
I've finished the book,
and Snuggly Jeff is dead.
And the readers are just gonna love it.
Paul, I still wish I could talk you out of this.
Snuggly Jeffis the most successful
children's book series ever.
Yeah, but I want to get
into writing more serious stuff.
You know, something
where the reader doesn't have
a load in his pants while he's looking at it.
Well, we'll talk about it
when you get back.
This just in.
The Weather Service has reported
a big snowstorm on its way.
Oh, my God! Stephen King!
Hey, this would make a neat story.
Done.
I'm your number-one fan.
Who... Who are you?
I'm Stewie Wilkes. I saved your life.
You were in a terrible car accident,
and you broke both your legs.
I taste lipstick.
- Am I wearing lipstick?
- Not anymore.
You know, I am a huge Snuggly Jeff fan.
I've read all the books.
Great. Hey, can you hand me
my cell phone?
I gotta call my agent.
She's probably worried sick about me.
It was destroyed in the accident.
- Well, can I use yours?
- No reception up here.
- Regular phone?
- Lines are down.
- Pay phone?
- Road's closed.
- E-mail?
- Dial-up.
- Fax?
- Paper jam.
- Morse code?
- Obsolete.
Brain-damaged bicycle courier?
I'm not quite so sure I can find my way.
Yeah, you're gonna be here a while.
Paul, quick question,
and feel free to say no,
but I couldn't help but notice the new
Snuggly Jeff manuscript in your bag.
And I was wondering if I could read it,
then kill you if I hate it?
Well, I guess that'd be okay.
Thank you, thank you, thank you!
Can I read it while I touch your ear
and suck my thumb?
- I guess.
- Goody, goody!
Mmm. Mmm.
- Stewie?
- I just finished the book, you dirty birdie.
How could you? He can't be dead.
Snuggly Jeff cannot be dead!
Look, Stewie.
I've gone as far as I can with Snuggly Jeff,
and I want to write
something more serious.
Well, you are gonna write Snuggly Jeff
back to life, Mr. Man.
Look, Stewie, first of all, you're insane,
and second of all,
I have to be inspired before I write.
Well, how about a little TV?
We now return
to Magnum, b. m.
Magnum, I found a fingerprint smudge
at the crime scene.
Do you have poo on your hands?
A little.
No, no, no. This won't do, Paul.
You can't just have Snuggly Jeff
magically brought back to life
by a child's wish.
It's insulting to the reader.
- What do you mean?
- Well, it's just bad storytelling.
Let's see. How can I explain this to you?
- Did you ever see the movie Contact?
- Yeah.
So, like, they spent a trillion dollars
building this mile-high space machine,
and Jake Busey blows it up.
So now they're all like,
"Oh, no! We can't use the space machine. "
But then this other guy's like,
"Hey, it just so happens
"I built another identical
trillion-dollar space machine
"at my own expense
on the other side of the world. "
And we're supposed to believe
no one noticed that?
Well, I stood up in the theater,
and I said, "No!
"You can't go into space
because the machine
"already got blown up
by Jake-cockadoody-Busey. "
- Start over!
- Fine.
But you're gonna have to go into town
and get me some more paper. I'm all out.
I don't know, Paul. Let me see
if I can get the Big Wheel started.
I don't know, Paul. It's not starting.
I'm afraid I'm gonna flood it.
Okay, I got it now. I'll see you in a bit.
He's too big for that car.
Mr. Sheldon?
Oh, my God! I'm saved!
Let's get out of here
before Stewie gets back.
My legs!
Now I'm gonna have to spend
the rest of my life in a wheelchair.
No, you're not.
Well, that's it, Stewie. The book is done.
- Can I go now?
- Oh, no, Paul. I'm not stupid.
If I let you go,
you'll just run straight to the police
and tell them I kidnapped you
and held you hostage
and fondled you while you were asleep.
No, I... Wait. What?
You'll tell them
that while you were sleeping
I did things to you
that you don't remember.
- You fondled me while I was asleep?
- Yeah.
- I don't think I like that.
- Well, it's done.
Everybody still awake? All right, big finish.
Now, you remember
that Stephen King story
when the guy went up to the empty hotel?
And there were those creepy twins?
And the guy was running around
with that ax?
And the kid talked to his finger?
Can't you see Stewie doing that?
Well, here's The Shawshank Redemption.
The first time I laid eyes on
Andy Dufresne, I didn't think much of him.
He was a fat drink of water,
the kind of drink of water that you know
your friend got from the bathroom
and not from the kitchen.
Five packs of cigarettes says
the fat one breaks first tonight.
You're on.
I'll take the Don Martin-looking one.
Welcome to Shawshank Prison.
I'll be your warden.
And even though I'm the only character
in this movie who's not a criminal,
I will be the bad guy.
Tomorrow's lunch is American chop suey,
so you came here on a good day.
Good lunch.
Look at those smiles.
All right, lights out, ladies.
It's funny because we are not ladies,
we are men.
Shut up.
A month went by before
Andy said two words to somebody.
As it turned out, that somebody was me.
Vagina boob.
Later, Andy came back
with more than two words.
I understand you're a man
who knows how to get things.
I've been known to procure
various and sundry items.
I don't understand what you just said.
I need stuff. Can you get it?
- What do you need?
- I need a rock hammer.
- What's it for?
- I carve Star Wars figurines out of stone,
but it's also for not tunneling
my way out of here.
Wow. Can you carve me a set
of women's private parts out of stone?
Sure. Or you could just have sex
with Helen Hunt.
We've only had one conversation, but
I can tell we're gonna be lifelong friends.
And since you're black and I'm white,
that makes it more special
for the audience.
Inspection.
- You Andy Dufresne?
- A little bit. You?
I'm just jiggling your balls.
What can I do for you?
I understand you make
Star Wars figurines.
Oh, Grievous. Wicked!
Well, anyway, I'm a pretty corrupt guy,
so I figured I could sell your figurines
and pocket the cash.
- What do you say?
- I don't know.
Come on. I'll even cripple that guy
who rapes you in the shower.
- But I like that guy.
- Too late.
My legs!
Two things never happened
again after that.
Bogs never walked again,
and Andy's farts never made
a sound again.
Thanks to the Star Wars
figurines Andy carved,
he landed a cushy job
cleaning the warden's office.
Okay, you clean up the warden's office
while I go pop out a pinecone.
Hey, you know what'd be funny?
You should take one of those records
and play it over the PA system.
No, you shouldn't do that,
but it'd be funny.
Okay, I'll be back
in three and a half minutes,
the average length of a song
on any long-playing album.
A few times
I've been around that track
So it's not just gonna happen like that
'Cause I ain't no hollaback girl
I ain't no hollaback girl
To this day, I have no idea
what that woman was singing about.
Like, literally no idea.
I don't know what a hollaback girl is,
but I have to imagine
it's a foul, disease-ridden thing
that wears too much makeup to cover up
the fact that it's a 47-year-old fish dog.
Andy, I think you know
why I've called you in here today.
A prison is an environment which requires
the highest level of discipline.
And that little stunt you pulled today...
That little stunt you pulled today made
a lot of people look very foolish.
Look, Warden, we got it rough in here.
I just thought we could use a little music.
Music is expressly forbidden
inside prison walls.
My God! How can you be so obtuse?
- What did you call me?
- Obtuse. You're being obtuse.
Two months in the hole.
- Or am I being obtuse?
- No, now you're being acute.
That time in the hole
changed old Andy.
I'm getting out of here tonight, Red.
I'm gonna take the poop pipe
to the crap swamp.
Wow. Where are you headed
once you get out?
- Zihuatanejo.
- Sounds fancy.
Well, actually, it's a filthy Mexican village.
Listen, Red, when you get out of here,
I want you to do something for me.
Up in a hayfield in Buxton, Maine,
under an old oak tree,
there's a rock that has
no earthly business being there.
It's black volcanic glass,
has no business being there.
Under that rock is a box
with something I want you to have.
Of course, now I think about it,
I've been in here 25 years.
All these landmarks are based
on possibly outdated observations.
That whole area could be
a Walmart by now.
If it is, pick yourself up some nice
cheap pants, and good life to you.
Inspection.
Dufresne? Dufresne?
Dufresne, you better get your ass out here
before you make me cut this sentence...
- Where is he? Where the hell is Dufresne?
- I don't know, sir.
Hey, we have almost the same voice.
Excuse me, I'm the prison doctor.
I'm here for Andy's check-up.
- Andy Dufresne?
- Yeah, Andy Dufresne.
- We can't find him.
- Well, that's no good.
All right, you two are gonna have to leave.
I want him found now.
Not after breakfast, not after CSI, now.
God, I'm so angry I could just throw
a rock at that poster of David Cassidy.
What the warden
and his boys didn't realize
was that Andy Dufresne had escaped
from Shawshank Prison the night before.
So no one told you
life was gonna be this way
Andy crawled to freedom
through 500 yards of foulness
I can't even imagine.
Andy Dufresne,
the man who crawled
through a river of poop
and came out clean on the other side.
Why he chose enchilada night,
I will never know.
Do you believe in your best judgment
that you have been rehabilitated?
Rehabilitated?
It's just a stupid made-up word
so boys like you can sit behind a desk,
wear a fancy suit, and feel important.
You're a jerk,
and I had sex with your mother last night.
And I swear to God, you let me out of here,
first thing I'm gonna do is kill again.
When I got out of Shawshank,
there was only one thing on my mind.
A promise I made to a friend
that I had to keep.
Walk along the stone wall
until you reach the tree,
and that's where you'll find the rock.
'"Dear Red, if you've come this far,
maybe you're willing to go a little further.
'"You remember the name
of the town in Mexico, right? '"
Shit!
What? Is that him? Is that...
No, no. Beach dog.
Is that Red? Is it... No, no. Not him either.
Where the hell is that jack-off?
There's, like, 1,200 bucks in that box.
Oh, my God. If he ran off with that,
oh, I am gonna be so pissed.
And what am I gonna do,
go to the authorities?
I just broke out of prison. Now what?
I gotta spend the rest of my life
here by myself?
Well, at least I won't have
to be self-conscious about my farting.
Well, that's our show.
Thank you, Stephen King.
We'll see you in court.
Now stay tuned for whatever
Fox is limping to the barn with.
Thank you for watching «Family Guy» on
www.FOX-fan.ru